<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document
	PUBLIC "-//Apache Software Foundation//DTD XDOC 1.0//EN"
	"http://maven.apache.org/dtd/xdoc_1_0.dtd">
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>Extension - Concept - PRG Pattern</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="PRG Pattern">
			<ul>
				<li>
					<a href="#Abstracts">Abstracts</a>
				</li>
				<li>
					<a href="#URL difference">URL difference</a>
				</li>
				<li>
					<a href="#PRG Pattern">PRG Pattern</a>
				</li>
				<li>
					<a href="#Showing self view">Showing self view</a>
				</li>
			</ul>
		</section>

		<section name="Abstracts">
			<p>
				Teeda Extension adopts PRG (POST-REDIRECT-GET) Pattern for view transition.
			</p>
			<p>
				PRG Pattern is that returning REDIRECT for requset of POST method,
				and showing the view of destination as response for GET method.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section name="URL differencer">
			<p>
				There is possibility to show contents that is different from URL in address bar of Web browser
                                when using page mode.
			</p>
			<p>The example below showing transition to bbb.html by submitting form of aaa.html</p>
			<img src="../../images/extension/concept/prg1.png" width="466"
				height="373" alt="URL difference" />
			<p>
				The transition from AaaPage of aaa.html to BbbPage of bbb.html by forward of Servlet API
                                shows URL aaa.html in address bar of web browser and contents of bbb.html.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section name="PRG Pattern">
			<p>
				Teeda adopts RPG pattern for making the contents that web browser shows not to be different
                                from URL in address bar of web browser.
			</p>
			<p>The example below shows transition from aaa.html to bbb.html by submitting form of aaa.html</p>
			<img src="../../images/extension/concept/prg2.png" width="466"
				height="448" alt="PRG Pattern" />
			<p>
				AaaPage of aaa.html returns REDIRECT to bbb.html as RESPONSE.
				So web browser requests bbb.html by GET method and shows bbb.html.
				The address bar of the web browser shows bbb.html that is destination of the REDIRECT, so there is no difference between URL and contents that is shown.
			</p>
			<p>
				Furthermore, because the contents that are shown by RPG Pattern is the result of GET REQUEST,
				web browser can cache the view. So "Back" and "Forward" buttons are available, it can prevent unintentional double submit.
			</p>
		</section>

		<section name="Showing self view">
			<p>
				Teeda uses RPG pattern only when transition to other Page.
				If POST BACK shows same page again, Teeda doesn't use RPG pattern, just returns RESPONSE.
			</p>
			<img src="../../images/extension/concept/prg3.png" width="466"
				height="380" alt="Showing self view" />
		</section>
	</body>
</document>
